GREG ROQUES

CONTACT

- 504.220.3832
- ☐ Greg@GregRoques.com
- GregRoques.com
- github.com/GregRoques
- in linkedin.com/in/GregRoques

SKILLS

Front End

HMTL • CSS • Sass • Bootstrap JavaScript • React • Redux

Back End

Node • Express • Python MySQL • PostGreSQL

Adobe CC

Illustrator • Indesign Photoshop • Premiere Pro

Google Analytics & MarketingGoogle Analytics and Adsense

PROJECTS

Full Stack Sift – March '19 sift.gregroques.com GitHub: https://bit.ly/2Hq8Kxz

Back End Dietactics – Feb. '19 dietactics.gregroques.com GitHub: https://bit.ly/2I4DHZr

Front End MealSleuth – Feb. '19 gregroques.com/mealsleuth GitHub: https://bit.ly/2taNpiC

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Development
DigitalCrafts '19 ~ Atlanta, GA

Graphic DesignTulane '10 ~ New Orleans, LA

B.A., Journalism LSU '04 ~ Baton Rouge, LA

ABOUT ME

Location: Atlanta, GA

I am a former creative director turned software developer with more than 10 years of experience managing award-winning print and online publications.

Primarily serving as an editor and art director in my previous roles, I began to witness a sharp shift from the printed page to the more modern digital canvas early in my career. While serving as creative director for a local magazine, I took the lead in establishing the brand's digital presence. I taught myself as much as I could about UI/Ux to ensure our interface and content best suited our readership, designed initial wireframes for the site, and learned HTML/CSS and basic JavaScript to optimize layouts and functionality within our CMS applications. Thanks to these efforts in collaboration with our development team, our website would quickly become the most awarded digital publication in the city.

After several years of pivoting towards digital strategy while continually learning to code, I realized my passion was to dive further into the development of the systems I was directing. I decided to fully dedicate my creative energies towards the design and development of efficient, user-focussed software solutions.

EXPERIENCE

DigitalCrafts Software Developer

November 2018 - March 2019 ~ Atlanta, GA

• Completed 16-week immersive full-time full-stack development program covering JavaScript, Python, including an emphasis on frameworks React/Redux, and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.

American Red Cross Regional Marketing and Communications Manager

March 2016 - November 2018 ~ New Orleans, LA

- Direct local digital and social media strategy and act as a media liaison and spokesperson during regional disasters. This included the Louisiana August 2016 floods and the 2017 and 2018 hurricane season responses.
- Responsible for recruitment, training and retention of Louisiana communications volunteer staff and internship programs across the region.
- Design and teach trainings for regional staff, boards and stakeholders: skills covered included becoming a spokesperson, social media management and digital storytelling.
- Led local media team responsible for generating more than \$1.8 million in earned media value during the first six months of the 2017-2018 fiscal year.
- Collaborate with development leadership to create promotional materials and campaigns advancing fundraising and service line brand exposure.

Where Y'at Magazine Creative Director

Jan. 2010 - March 2016 ~ New Orleans, LA

- Conceptualized and assigned editorial for print and digital publications.
- Designed print and digital advertisements and editorial layouts.
- Served as the digital director, managing the website, eNewsletter and social media content creation and editorial calendar.
- Responsible for staff recruitment, management and retention; this included leading a team of approximately 30 freelancers, interns and editorial managers.
- Led the audience development strategy rebranding the publication to target the city's young professional market. This included redesigning the print publication and overseeing the development of an upgraded website and digital presence.